Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
- Series III. Consulting
  - Subseries II. Energy
    - IFR, letters to preserve project, summer '93, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - IFR, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - DOE letter, AFEI, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - RTR (Radkowsky Thorium Fuel/Reactor), 1997 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - RTR Design, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Kursu: Nuclear Stewardship, 1997-1998 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - LMFBR, incl. meeting, (n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Feldhamer, reactors, 1964, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Gabon (Oklo) Reactor, 1974, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - SENSE, energy policy, 1974-1979 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Breeder, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Livermore, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Oak Ridge, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - RDD, Fast breeder safety, 1975, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Schmidt, reactor safety, 1975-1977 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - TMI Accident, 1981, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Energy, Radkowsky - Feldhamer, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Argonne, Metal Breeder, 1984, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Garwin, IFR, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Fusion Breeders, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - LA 'Science', (n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Program, Los Al, (n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Los Alamos Miscell., 1973-1975 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - New Mexico Lab Facilities, 1975, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - LASL 1980, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - DOE contract, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - LAMPF, 1984-1988 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - LAMPF, 1988, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - History Los Alamos, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Los Alamos '91, LAMPF, recon., 1991 (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - LA - Bulletin, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - LA Fellows, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - LA Fellows, Hecker, 1992, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Los Alamos 1992, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 31)
    - Los Alamos security refresher briefing, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 32)
    - The Bulletin, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 33)
    - Cornell Workshop, Defense conversion of Los Alamos, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 34)
    - Critics of LANL, Glorieta, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - LANL 2000 conference, Glorieta, NM, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - LANL 2000 conference, Glorieta, NM, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - Los Al. Summer '93, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 38)
    - Op-Ed, labs, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 39)
    - 5th International Cold Fusion Conference, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - Argonne and other reports, 1993-1995 (Box 37, Folder 41)
    - Reports: IFR and subcritical experiments, 1994-1997 (Box 37, Folder 42)
    - Advisory Committee (ANL), (n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 43)
    - Max Carbon, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 44)
    - Ad Hoc Panel, Meson Factories 1 of 3, 1960-1964 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Ad Hoc Panel, Meson Factories 2 of 3, 1960-1964 (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Ad Hoc Panel, Meson Factories 3 of 3, 1960-1964 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Detroit Edison, FBR Report, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - GE Contract Work, 1953-1955 (Box 57, Folder 23)
    - General Atomic, Case for GCFR, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 24)
    - GE, One-Velocity Diffusion Problem, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 25)
    - Sandia Labs, Fusion Hybrid Reactor, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 26)
    - The Properties of Atomic Nuclei, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 27)
    - DOE Correspondence, Fusion Breeders, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 28)
    - Power Reactor Development Company Testimonies to US Atomic Energy Commission, Operating License, 1961-1965 (Box 57, Folder 29)
    - APDA Memo, Fermi Core A, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 30)
    - Gernal Atomic, Reactivity Lifetime Calc. for Thermal Reactors, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 31)
    - KMS, Lubin, 1974, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 32)
    - Reactors, 1970-1975 (Box 57, Folder 33)
    - Hertzberg, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Hertzberg, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Fusion, 1974, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Laser Solenoid, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Laser Heated Solenoid, 1974-1976 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Math. Sci. NW, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - EPA and NRC on WASH-1400, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Reactor Safety, 1970-1975 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Reactor Safety, AIF, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Reactor Safety, Cancer Risks, 1974-1975 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - APS Panel, Reactor Safety Symposium, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Fuel for Breeders, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Reactor Safety, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Reactor Safety, 1970-1975 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Fusion Reactors, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Gas Cooled Fast Breeder, notes from Jan. trip 1974, 1972, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - LMFBR, 1972-1974 (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Fast Reactor, 1972-1974 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - LMFBR safety papers, Jan. '75, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 19)
    - Fast Reactor Safety '73-'74, 1973-1974 (Box 58, Folder 20)
    - GAO-LMFBR and critique of GAO, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - Nucl. Safeguards Conf., 1976 (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - My paper and Wingspread Info., also Nero, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Thorium Fuel and its use in Helium-Coolded Reactors, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - ONR, Contract, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - AVCO Travel, 1981, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Nuclear Power, 1976, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Breeder Reactors, 1975 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Irises in Waveguides, 1942 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Laser Fusion, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - High Energy Phenomena, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 7)
- Series IV. Cornell
  Material relevant to Bethe’s role as a member of the Cornell University faculty and Physics Department. Includes correspondence and memoranda, notes and clippings.
  - Subseries I. General Cornell University
    Records related to Cornell University, the faculty, and Bethe’s participation in both. Includes memoranda and clippings. Clipping topics range from Bethe himself, to events at Cornell and/or in the Ithaca Community, such as the Great Pumpkin Prank of 1997. Includes material on the student take-over of the Willard Straight Student Union in 1969.
    - Cornell University Business, 1953, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - University Faculty, Business misc, 1953-1955 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - University Faculty, misc., 1957-1965 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Anti-trust suit, 1991-1992 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Campus Issues, 1993-1998 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 1, 1958-1994 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 2, 1968-2001 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 3, 1963-1969 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 4, 1950-1957 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 5, 1950-1999 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 6, 1982-2003 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Bethe, Hans A. Emeritus, 7, 1957-2001 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Issues/Events: Student Unionization, R.A. training, 1990-2003 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Issues/Events: Lottery, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Issues/Events: Totem Pole, 1994-2001 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Issues/Events: Four Freshmen, 1995-1998 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Issues/Events: Comatose Woman, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Issues/Events: Deer in Gorge, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Issues/Events: Pumpkin Prank 1, 1997-1998 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Issues/Events: Pumpkin Prank 2, 1997-1998 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Issues/Events: Cornell Review. Ebonics Controversy, 1997-2001 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Issues/Events: Dissection, 1999-2002 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Cornell, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Cornell Faculty, 1952 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Cornell faculty meetings, grad school etc., 1955-1956 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Cornell Faculty, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Cornell Memos, 1952-1953 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Curriculum, 1960-1969 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Cornell Politics, 1965-1970 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Bethe Resolution Committee, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Bethe Resolution Committee, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Cranch Committee, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Prisoners Committee, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Profs at large, 1971-1972 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Andrew White Prof. at Large 1974, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Itineraries, 1998 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Bethe 80th Birthday, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Bethe 90th Birthday, APS Award, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Calender, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Corson, Energy Studies at Cornell, 1975 (Box 59, Folder 45)
    - Cornell 1969, Bethe Committee: Academic Responsibilities of the Faculty, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 46)
    - Bethe's 80th Birthday Volume of Talks, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 47)
    - Cornell Centennial, 1965 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Bethe University appointment letters and documents, 1928-1945 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Cornell Senate materials, 1970 (Box 112, Folder 3-4)
    - Cornell Senate materials, 1970-1971 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Cornell Senate materials and clippings, 1970, 1989 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Cornell turmoil clippings and notes, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 7-12)
    - Cornell turmoil: incidental intelligence (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Turmoil at Harvard and Cornell, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - Cornell related newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - Cornell turmoil materials, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - Cornell annual reports, 1962-1968 (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - Subseries II. Physics Department
    Records reflecting Bethe’s role as a member of the physics faculty. Includes material from courses Bethe taught at Cornell, including lecture notes and problems/exam questions. Also includes information on Cornell’s Newman Lab.
    - Theoretical Physics in Newman Lab, 1952, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Cornell Nuclear Reactor, 1956-1960 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Lab of Nuclear studies Publications, 1958-1965 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Annual Report [to NSF], 1968-1972 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Applications, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Lab of Nuclear Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - Science 645, (n.d.) (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - Grad Assistants, Res. Associates, 1959-1970 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - LASSP, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - 574, Time-dependent theory, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - Courses, 1965-1970 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - Asst. Profs. and Res. Associates, 1967-1970 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - Wigner-Eckart Exams, 1967-1972 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - 574, Field Theory, 1969-1972 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - Nuclear Physics lectures, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - Senior Professorship, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - Cornell Dept., 1971-1973 (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - 561, Fall '72, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Problems 561, Electrodynamics, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - 572, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 572 Problems, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - History of Atomic Theory, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Exam, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Questionnaires-->Problem Solving, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - NSF Research Proposal, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Cornell Physics Dept., 1964 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Cornell Physics misc., 1960, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Cornell Physics, Graduate Conference, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Frank Newman, Bethe, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Weizsäcker I, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Weizsäcker II, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Nuc. Lab, 40yrs, 1983-1985 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Physics, 1947-1962. (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Cornell Lab, 1952-1953 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Lab, travel expenses, 1953-1954 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Nuclear Physics Labs Directory, (n.d.) (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Physics Dept Reorganization, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - 24 Oct. 1975, Bethe's retirement, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies, Cornell, 1945, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies 1 of 5, Feynman, 1943-1950 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies 2 of 5, Budget, 1949, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies 3 of 5, Budget, 1965-1974 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies 4 of 5, Budget, 1970-1972 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies 5 of 5, Budget, 1967, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1999, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Work in Theoretical Physics at Cornell, (n.d.) (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Reactor Committee, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 48)
    - Physics Faculty, 1960, 1961 (Box 59, Folder 49)
    - Physics Forum, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 50)
    - F. J. Dyson Lecture Course 491, Advanced Quantum Theory, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 51)
    - Cornell lecture notes and transparencies (Box 112, Folder 18-24)
    - Palevi lectures: Iran, 1976 or 1977 (Box 112, Folder 25)
    - Speech delivered at Cornell: Test ban and inspection, 1958 (Box 112, Folder 26)
- Series V. Correspondence
  This series includes all correspondence that Bethe or his secretaries filed together in a systematic way.
  - Subseries I. Alphabetic by Name or Topic
    These files are labeled with the name of a person or of a topic, such as "Canadian Conference (Natl. Research Council).” They are ordered alphabetically.
    - 11th International Conference on High Energy Physics, CERN July 1962, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 45)
    - AAAS Recommendations, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 46)
    - AEC Computing Facility, 1953-1955 (Box 37, Folder 47)
    - Air Force, 1954-1957 (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - Air Research and Development Command, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 49)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1962, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - American Association of Physics Teachers, 1954, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 51)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1953 (Box 37, Folder 52)
    - American Astronomical Society, 1961-1970 (Box 37, Folder 53)
    - American Institute of Physics 1 of 4 (1958-1960), 1958-1960 (Box 37, Folder 54)
    - American Institute of Physics 2 of 4 (1957, 1958), 1957, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 55)
    - American Institute of Physics 3 of 4 (1956), 1956 (Box 37, Folder 56)
    - American Institute of Physics 4 of 4 (1956, 1957), 1956, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 57)
    - American Nuclear Society 1of 2, 1956-1962 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - American Nuclear Society 2 of 2, 1956-1962 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1956-1971 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - American Physical Society, 1955-1960, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Annual Review of Nuclear Science, Nuclear Matter, HAB, Vol. 21, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Astrophysical Journal, (n.d.) (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - APDA 1 of 2 (1955-1962), 1955-1962 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - APDA 2 of 2 (1956-1962), 1956-1962 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Applicants (1952, 1953), 1952, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Applicants, 1953-1954 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Applications for 1955/56, 1955, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Applications for Instructor Research Positions, 1964-1966 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Applications for Instructor Research Positions, 1965-1967 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Applications for Instructor Research Positions, 1966-1968 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Applications for Instructor Research Positions, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Articles to write, 1978-1980 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Aspen Institute, 1955-1971 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1960, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Atomic Power Development Associates, Inc., 1957-1967 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - 'Atoms for Peace' Conference, Geneva - 1955, August, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Norman Austern, 1952-1961 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - AVCO - Correspondence with L. P. Smith, 1956-1958 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - AVCO - General Correspondence, 1955-1981 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - AVCO Contract, AVCO Systems Division, 1956-1970 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - AVCO Mfg. Co., New York Office, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - AVCO, misc. correspondence (1958-1960), 1958-1960 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - AVCO-Everett, 1957-1967 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - AVCO-RAD, 1964, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Bacher, Robert F., 1956-1966 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Sven-Olof Backman, 1972, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Bahcall, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Bakerian Lecture, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Baym, Gordon, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - David B. Beard, 1956-1964 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Bell, Thomas L, 1971-1972 (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Bethe - Personal, 1940-1981 (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Bethe - Personal, 1952-1955 (Box 38, Folder 37)
    - Bethe and Swanseen Correspondence, trip to Cambridge, 1955-1956 (Box 38, Folder 38)
    - Binaries, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 39)
    - Blaha, Stephen, 1972-1973 (Box 38, Folder 40)
    - Book - Elementary Nuclear Physics, Morrison-Bethe, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 41)
    - Book 'Mesons and Fields', contract etc, 1954, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 42)
    - Book requisitions for Univ., 1954 (Box 38, Folder 43)
    - Book Review, Brighter than a Thousand Suns by Jungk, 1958, 1959 (Box 38, Folder 44)
    - Baird H. Brandow, 1958-1972 (Box 38, Folder 45)
    - Brazil visit, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 46)
    - Gregory Breit, 1960-1967 (Box 38, Folder 47)
    - Brodsky, Stanley J., 1969 (Box 38, Folder 48)
    - Brookhaven, misc., 1956, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 49)
    - Brout, Robert, 1962-1964 (Box 38, Folder 50)
    - Gerald E. Brown, 1957-1966 (Box 38, Folder 51)
    - Laurie M. Brown, 1957, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 52)
    - Stanley G. Brown, 1965, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 53)
    - Keith A. Brueckner, 1957-1965 (Box 38, Folder 54)
    - Brueckner and Gammel, 1956, 1957 (Box 38, Folder 55)
    - The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1956-1981 (Box 38, Folder 56)
    - Burrows Correspondence, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 57)
    - Cambridge trip, Fulbright info, 1954-1956 (Box 38, Folder 58)
    - Canadian Conference (Natl. Research Council), 1955 (Box 38, Folder 59)
    - Capps, Richard H., 1956-1962 (Box 38, Folder 60)
    - Carruthers, Peter, 1959-1969 (Box 38, Folder 61)
    - Chadwick, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 62)
    - Christian Science, (n.d.) (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1954, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Cisler, Detroit Edison Company, 1954, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Contogouris, Andreas, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Convair, 1955-1961 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Cooper, Frederick M., 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Cornell Convocation, N.Y.C., March 9, 1968, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Corresp. Re--Wilson Invention, 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Corresp. w/ Science, Gerry, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Council for a Livable World, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Crewther, Rodney J., 1971 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Cromer, Alan, 1956-1961 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Torolf Dahlblom, 1963-1967 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Fred de Hoffmann, 1955-1962 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - F. J. Dyson - Correspondence, 1955-1967 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - P. P. Ewald, 1986-1988 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - FAS correspondence, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Fowler, Chandra, 1972-1977 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Garwin-Fermi, (n.d.) (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Hammel, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Hammel: Interview Committee, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Henry Hurwitz Tribute, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Intnl. Symposium on Contemporary Physics, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - IQM. Correspondence on book, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Jain, Adeshwar P., 1953-1969 (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - Kawaguchi, Masaaki, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - Keh-Ying Lin, 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - Michael W. Kirson, 1960-1966 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Kiu Suk Suh, 1961-1962 (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - Letter from John Negele re. Feshbach Chair, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Letter to Prof. Samuel, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Lin, Ying-Chi, 1965-1968 (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - McNamara, Book Forward, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - Mehra and letter from Dick Garwing, 1985, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - Meson reports, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - Mezzacappa, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1968, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 41)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1973-1995 (Box 39, Folder 42)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 43)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1997, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 44)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 45)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - Misc. German correspondence, 1984, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 47)
    - MIT press request - declined and other requests, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 48)
    - Steven Moszkowski, 1960-1964 (Box 39, Folder 49)
    - N. W. Ayer and Son, 1953, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 50)
    - Nitya R. Nath, 1965-1972 (Box 39, Folder 51)
    - Nath, N./N. Nath--thesis, 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 52)
    - National Youth Conference on the Atom, Chicago Nov. 1961, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 53)
    - Naval Research (Dept. of), 1967-1969 (Box 39, Folder 54)
    - Negele, John William, 1968-1970 (Box 39, Folder 55)
    - Nemeth, Judit, 1964-1968 (Box 39, Folder 56)
    - Harald A. Neuer, 1962-1963 (Box 39, Folder 57)
    - Michael Nieto, 1964-1966 (Box 39, Folder 58)
    - Nobel, autograph requests (for signature), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 59)
    - Nobel Prize [Lecture], 1967 (Box 39, Folder 60)
    - More Nobel, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 61)
    - Nomination of Khariton, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 62)
    - Notes on various papers, letters, Ithaca, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 63)
    - Opportunities for participation in space flight, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 64)
    - Otrabanda Company, Science Play, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 65)
    - r-process, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 66)
    - Radkowski, 1990's (Box 39, Folder 67)
    - Roderick V. Reid., Jr., 1968-1969 (Box 39, Folder 68)
    - Request for interviews, Faxes, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 69)
    - SAGE, 1997-1998 (Box 39, Folder 70)
    - Scheerbaum, Robert R., 1969 (Box 39, Folder 71)
    - Schools / Penn State, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 72)
    - Science Archives Correspondence, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 73)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1957-1969 (Box 39, Folder 74)
    - Solar Neutrinos Letter, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 75)
    - Rep. Solarz, Tomahawk missiles, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 76)
    - Solvay Conference, Brussels Oct. 1961, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 77)
    - Sommerfeld to Einstein, (n.d.) (Box 39, Folder 78)
    - Steen, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 79)
    - Subbaraman, M. S., 1968 (Box 39, Folder 80)
    - Subbarao, Krishnappa, 1971-1973 (Box 39, Folder 81)
    - M. K. Sundaresan, 1955-1960 (Box 39, Folder 82)
    - Hirotaka Sugawara, 1965 (Box 39, Folder 83)
    - Tata, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 84)
    - Terazawa, Hidezumi, 1968-1971 (Box 39, Folder 85)
    - Textbooks for Courses, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 86)
    - Thesis Requirements, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 87)
    - Travel, 1952-1954 (Box 39, Folder 88)
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Committee, 1957-1964 (Box 39, Folder 89)
    - W. A. Benjamin, Inc., 1964-1970 (Box 39, Folder 90)
    - Weisberger, William, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 91)
    - Wiley and Sons Publishers, 1954-1960 (Box 39, Folder 92)
    - Wilson correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 39, Folder 93)
    - T. P. Wright--Univ. (Vice Pres. for Research), 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 94)
    - Bethe - Kohler Correspondence, 1961-1985 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Convocation of Laureates, Carnegie-Mellon, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Fred Jerome Correspondence, 'The Einstein File', 1996 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Job Openings, 1958 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - LASSP Director, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - List of my letters in Archives, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Mail, 1990-1993, 1990-1993 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Correspondence, (n.d.) (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1967, 1968 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1976-1993 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - German Correspondence, 1935 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Nat. Academy, 1974, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Nobel File, 1946, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 20)